<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[ObisidianNotes]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>ObisidianNotes</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 09:24:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 09:24:14 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[U1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>When vivo Senior Director for Brand Strategy and CEIBS alumnus Seon Hwang moved to Shanghai from his native Korea to do an MBA in 2010, he did so with his mid-to-long term sights set on developing his career in China by helping a Chinese company go global. Two years later, however, as he and the rest of his class were graduating, the types of roles Seon had envisioned himself filling in China still didn't really exist in any great number.<br>
2010 年，vivo 品牌战略高级总监、中欧国际工商学院校友 Seon Hwang 从韩国来到上海攻读 MBA，他的中长期目标是帮助一家中国公司走向世界，从而在中国发展自己的职业生涯。然而，两年后，当他和同班同学毕业时，Seon 设想自己在中国担任的职位类型仍然并不多见。<br>
"At the time, there weren't many opportunities for foreigners to work for a globalising Chinese company, Instead, I got several offers, all from non-Chinese companies, including three from Korea," Seon recalls. "They were good positions, but I rejected most of them because there was no reason for me to go back to Korea or work for a Korean company. In the end, l chose to take a position with BMW Group China.<br>
“当时，外国人在全球化的中国公司工作的机会并不多，相反，我收到了几份工作邀请，全部来自非中国公司，其中有三家来自韩国，”Seon 回忆道。“这些职位都很不错，但我拒绝了大部分，因为我没有理由回到韩国或为韩国公司工作。最后，我选择了宝马集团中国分公司。<br>
During his time at BMW, Seon developed his real-world knowledge of the Chinese market and established a proven track record in sales and marketing. But, he also continued to hold onto his aspiration of going global with a Chinese company. Looking back now, he says he realises that he was really just ahead of the curve--if only just.<br>
在宝马任职期间，Seon 积累了对中国市场的实际了解，并在销售和营销方面取得了良好的业绩。但他也一直怀揣着与中国公司一起走向世界的愿望。现在回想起来，他说他意识到自己真的走在了时代的前面——即使只是刚刚走在前面。<br>
The period that followed proved to be a major watershed for Chinese brands going global, with names such as Huawei, Lenovo, and DJI all staking out spots on the world map. Nevertheless, it wasn't until 2017 that Seon finally received his first serious recruiting call from a Chinese company in the form of Guangdong-based smartphone manufacturer vivo. "Vivo's ambition to become an even bigger smartphone player in China and the world is growing and they were looking for someone with sufficient experience and understanding of branding and strategy who as also equipped with knowledge of both Chinese and global business and culture," he explains. "Their HR department contacted me directly and asked me if l'd consider working for them. I'm quite a big fan of smartphones and other gadgets. So, in the end, they were able to convince me to join them."<br>
随后的一段时间成为中国品牌走向全球的重要分水岭，华为、联想和大疆等品牌都在世界地图上占据一席之地。然而，直到 2017 年，Seon 才终于接到了第一通来自中国公司的正式招聘电话，这家公司就是广东的智能手机制造商 vivo。“Vivo 想要成为中国乃至全球更大的智能手机制造商，他们正在寻求一个拥有足够经验和品牌及战略理解力的人，同时还要了解中国和全球商业和文化，”他解释道。“他们的人力资源部门直接联系了我，问我是否愿意为他们工作。我非常喜欢智能手机和小装置。所以，最终，他们说服了我加入他们。”<br>
Since joining vivo, Seon says he has found a good fit with the organization's culture and he now leads a team responsible for, among other things, the company's overall brand strategy, product positioning, and corporate identity As such, he plays a pivotal role for a brand which has established itself as China's number two smartphone company by appealing primarily to younger customers, Despite vivo's success, he says the company's leadership still looks to him to continue upgrading and improving the way things are done.<br>
Seon 表示，自从加入 vivo 以来，他发现自己非常适应公司的文化，现在他领导的团队负责公司的整体品牌战略、产品定位和企业形象等事务。因此，他对这个通过主要吸引年轻客户而成为中国第二大智能手机公司的品牌扮演着关键的角色。尽管 vivo 取得了成功，但他表示，公司领导层仍希望他继续升级和改进工作方式。<br>
"As a foreigner working at a Chinese company, what the company needs from me is systematic thinking, logic, and processes," he states, "So, I contribute a lot with product positioning, brand strategy, and setting the rules we apply when we promote our products, in order to ensure we grow our influence. These are things they want to learn."<br>
“作为一个在中国公司工作的外国人，公司需要我具备系统思维、逻辑和流程。”他说，“所以，我在产品定位、品牌战略、产品推广规则等方面做出了很多贡献，确保我们的影响力不断扩大。这些都是公司想学的东西。”<br>
To put things into perspective, when Seon arrived at CEIBS, vivo was only one year old. And, while its parent company, BuBuGao Electronics, was established in 1995 by Western standards, its history spans a comparatively short period of time. On the upside, Seon says that being on the leading edge of a young organisation's global aspirations has put him in a position where he is closer to many of the company's biggest decision-makers.<br>
从整体上看，当 Seon 来到中欧时，vivo 才刚刚成立一年。而尽管其母公司步步高电子按照西方标准成立于 1995 年，但其历史却相对较短。从好的方面来看，Seon 表示，站在一家年轻组织的全球抱负的前沿，使他能够更接近公司许多最大的决策者。<br>
"The distance to top management is really small and I often report directly to the CEO and the company's, board members," Seon says "At the same time, relative to other industries, the Chinese tech and communications industries are quite new. So companies like vivo are very open-minded, very straightforward and very fast-moving."<br>
“与高层管理人员之间的距离非常小，我经常直接向首席执行官和公司董事会成员汇报，”Seon 说道，“与此同时，相对于其他行业，中国的科技和通信行业还很新。因此，像 vivo 这样的公司思想非常开放、非常直率，而且行动非常迅速。”<br>
Seon's time at vivo has taken him into some pretty exciting territory including helping the company tap into more overseas markets and negotiating major sponsorship deals with organisations such as FIFA and the NBA.  And, while it is clear that he made the right decision in joining vivo, he admits that when he was first approached by the company, he still had to overcome certain apprehension about finally going to work for a Chinese employer.<br>
Seon 在 vi​​vo 的工作经历让他涉足了一些相当令人兴奋的领域，包括帮助公司开拓更多海外市场，并与国际足联和 NBA 等组织谈判重大赞助协议。虽然加入 vivo 的决定显然是正确的，但他承认，当公司第一次联系他时，他仍然不得不克服一些对于最终为中国雇主工作的担忧。<br>
"A lot of foreigners, when they get a job offer from a Chinese company, worry about the corporate culture, that the company may be very conservative, or that only Chinese employees can survive there," he says, "But, it's really case-by-case and every company has a different culture and different values, Also, for non-Chinese students, it's really important that they learn the language here, as it's the best way to understand Chinese history, culture, and ideas."<br>
“很多外国人在收到中国公司的工作邀请时，都会担心公司的企业文化，担心公司可能非常保守，或者只有中国员工才能在那里生存，”他说，“但这真的要因人而异，每家公司都有不同的文化和价值观。此外，对于非中国学生来说，在这里学习语言非常重要，因为这是了解中国历史、文化和思想的最好方式。”<br>
Whether intentionally or not, Seon and his team are now playing an important role in educating others about what it is like working with Chinese companies by creating opportunities to welcome students into their workplace to see first-hand how the company operates——something nearly 50 CElBS MBA students did as part of their China module in Shenzhen.<br>
不管有意还是无意，Seon 和他的团队现在正发挥着重要作用，他们创造机会欢迎学生到他们的工作场所亲眼看看公司的运作方式，让其他人了解与中国公司合作是什么样的——近 50 名 CElBS MBA 学生在深圳学习中国课程时就这么做了。<br>
"We invite them to our vivo Innovation Lab concept store, for example, and introduce them to our brand, the products, the experience. and the brand culture," Seon explains. “They might want to come and work with us in the future, but they don't have any connections here or they didn't really have an understanding of vivo so this is kind of the first step."<br>
“例如，我们邀请他们参观我们的 vivo 创新实验室概念店，向他们介绍我们的品牌、产品、体验和品牌文化，”Seon 解释道。“他们可能希望将来来与我们合作，但他们在这里没有任何关系，或者他们对 vivo 并不真正了解，所以这只是第一步。”<br>
In 2018, Seon led a vivo campus recruitment event at CEIBS aimed at hiring global talent and, to date, he has already hired five CEIBS graduates for his team. In 2019, he represented vivo at INNOVATEChina2019, serving as a judge for the CElBS MBA student-organised business proposal competition, And while he agrees that initiatives like these do a lot to close the gap between potential employers and up-and-coming talent, he strongly suggests that MBAs who truly want to work with Chinese companies do everything they can to leverage the school's alumni network.<br>
2018 年，Seon 领导了中欧国际工商学院的一场 vivo 校园招聘活动，旨在招聘全球人才。到目前为止，他已经为自己的团队招聘了五名中欧毕业生。2019 年，他代表 vivo 参加了 INNOVATEChina2019，并担任中欧国际工商学院 MBA 学生组织的商业计划竞赛评委。虽然他同意此类举措有助于缩小潜在雇主和后起之秀人才之间的差距，但他强烈建议真正想与中国公司合作的 MBA 尽一切可能利用学校的校友网络。<br>
"When I was a student, I was always looking for alumni. I'd send them e-mails and say, 'I would like to have a chat, let's have coffee', because I really wanted to work in China," he says, "If you're looking for an opportunity with a Chinese company, contact alumni and do research If students want to come to vivo, they can call me and have a brief chat and ask me about the culture and life here."<br>
“当我还是学生时，我总是在寻找校友。我会给他们发电子邮件，说‘我想聊聊，我们喝杯咖啡吧’，因为我真的很想在中国工作，”他说，“如果你正在寻找一家中国公司的机会，那就联系校友并做些调查。如果学生想来 vivo，他们可以给我打电话，简短地聊聊，问问这里的文化和生活。”<br>
Ultimately, Seon says he sees some important parallels between CEIBS and vivo and that he hopes to see more opportunities for both brands to grow together in the future.<br>
最后，Seon 表示他看到了中欧和 vivo 之间一些重要的相似之处，并希望看到两个品牌在未来有更多共同成长的机会。<br>
"CEIBS is a global top-tier school and it's doing very well, but the school's brand recognition is still somewhat limited in many countries, so the situation is quite similar to vivo's," he concludes. "The school is also trying to go global, and I hope that in the future more people will learn about CEIBS. This is something that I really want to see."<br>
“中欧是一所全球顶级商学院，而且发展得很好，但该学院的品牌知名度在许多国家仍然有限，因此情况与 vivo 非常相似，”他总结道。“中欧也在努力走向全球，我希望未来会有更多人了解中欧。这是我真正想看到的。”<br><br>"Brand sacrifice" means companies, not consumers, feel the pain.<br>
“品牌牺牲”意味着企业而非消费者承受痛苦。<br>
Melting glaciers. Increasing obesity, Oppressed workers. There are a lot of things to worry about these days. Business researchers often ask how individual behavior can be changed to mitigate the ill effects of risk-laden phenomena-how to get consumers to make sacrifices so business doesn't have to pay for problems like underpaid workers and rising obesity levels. But they usually find that such changes are incredibly difficult to engineer. Marketers, on the other hand, usually want to know where the opportunities lie-even in global problems like climate change. For some companies the opportunity both to address the world's problems and to attract more customers lies in letting individuals do what they have always done well—consume—and having the brands make sacrifices instead.<br>
冰川融化。肥胖增加，工人受压迫。如今有很多事情需要担忧。商业研究人员经常询问如何改变个人行为以减轻风险现象的不良影响——如何让消费者做出牺牲，从而使企业不必为工人低薪和肥胖问题买单。但他们通常发现，这样的改变非常难以实现。而营销人员则通常想知道机会在哪里——即使在全球性问题如气候变化中。对于一些公司来说，既能解决世界问题又能吸引更多客户的机会在于让个人继续他们一直擅长的事情——消费，而品牌则做出牺牲。<br>
Since well before the Mad Men era, brand marketers have conditioned us to think that we should look to them to meet our everchanging needs (and whims) easily, often inexpensively, and usually without guilt. You may have thought this gluttonous consumption is how we arrived at overflowing landfills, immense plastic gyres floating around the Pacific Ocean, and vastly underpaid workers in low-wage countries Perhaps. But now, according to a recent report from Trend Watching, an increasing number of brands are willing to undertake the costs necessary to reverse those social ills, and more, without affecting the consumers' consumption habits. They call it "brand sacrifice".<br>
早在《广告狂人》时代之前，品牌营销人员就让我们认为我们应该依靠他们来轻松、通常廉价且通常没有负罪感地满足我们不断变化的需求（和心血来潮）。你可能认为这种暴饮暴食的消费导致了垃圾填埋场的溢出、太平洋上巨大的塑料旋涡以及低工资国家的工人被严重低薪。也许是这样。但现在，根据Trend Watching的一份最新报告，越来越多的品牌愿意承担逆转这些社会弊病所需的成本，而不影响消费者的消费习惯。他们称之为“品牌牺牲”。<br>
Trend Watching gives examples of brand sacrifice in each three categories:<br>
Sacrifice for the self, CVS's decision to stop selling tobacco products. The company sacrifices revenue in order to help its customers lead healthier lives, even when competitors like Walgreens decline to follow.<br>
Sacrifice for society, Intel stopped using conflict minerals in its chips. Its customers (and all of the end users who buy an “Intel Inside” product) can feel better about a cleaner and less controversial supply chain.<br>
Sacrifice for the planet, Some clothing brands and retailers stopped selling angora wool because of animal cruelty issues in production.<br>
TrendWatching在每个类别中都给出了品牌牺牲的例子：<br>
自我牺牲，CVS决定停止销售烟草制品。该公司牺牲收入以帮助客户过上更健康的生活，即使竞争对手如Walgreens拒绝效仿。<br>
为社会牺牲，英特尔停止在其芯片中使用冲突矿物。其客户（以及所有购买“Intel Inside”产品的最终用户）可以对更清洁、更少争议的供应链感到更好。<br>
为地球牺牲，一些服装品牌和零售商因生产中的动物虐待问题停止销售安哥拉羊毛。<br>
Of course, not every sacrifice fits neatly into one category. Chipotle made news a few months back when it stopped selling pork in some of its restaurants because a supplier had failed to meet the company's animal care requirements. Chipotle's stringent commitment to meat from antibiotic-free animals raised in humane conditions can be seen as both a sacrifice for the self (healthier offerings for its customers) and the planet (encouraging sustainable farming practices). The company's stock suffered when it took a stand that sacrificed sales. But when I spoke to Maxwell Luthy, director of trends and insights at TrendWatching, he told me he believes the enduring loyalty Chipotle engendered by its sacrifice outweighs the short-term cost.<br>
当然，并不是每种牺牲都能整齐地归入一个类别。几个月前，Chipotle因为供应商未能满足公司的动物护理要求而停止在其一些餐厅销售猪肉，这一消息引起了关注。Chipotle对无抗生素动物在人道条件下饲养的严格承诺可以被视为既是自我牺牲（为客户提供更健康的选择），也是为地球牺牲（鼓励可持续农业实践）。当公司采取立场牺牲销售时，其股票受到了影响。但当我与TrendWatching的趋势与洞察总监Maxwell Luthy交谈时，他告诉我，他相信Chipotle通过牺牲所产生的持久忠诚度超过了短期成本。<br>
Brand sacrifice initially hit me as a through-the-looking-glass moment in which everything is turned upside down. However, digging more deeply, I found evidence that responsible company action may be one way of undoing what more than a century of growing consumerism has created-and business is benefitting in the process. Take Patagonia, for example. The company is several years into a "buy less" campaign that asks current customers to wear what they have until it is threadbare The result: an increase in sales. CEO Yvon Chouinard told Inc. magazine, "I know it sounds crazy, but every time I have made a decision that is best for the planet, I have made money. Our customers know that-and they want to be part of that environmental commitment. "What is not clear is whether these are old customers feeling good about trading up, or new customers migrating from brands less willing to sacrifice.<br>
品牌牺牲最初让我感觉像是一个透过镜子的时刻，一切都颠倒了。然而，更深入地挖掘，我发现负责任的公司行动可能是解决一个多世纪不断增长的消费主义所带来的问题的一种方式——而且企业在这一过程中受益。以Patagonia为例。这家公司已经进行了数年的“少买”运动，要求现有客户穿着他们已有的衣物直到破烂不堪。结果：销售额增加。CEO Yvon Chouinard告诉《Inc.》杂志：“我知道这听起来很疯狂，但每次我做出对地球最好的决定时，我都赚钱了。我们的客户知道这一点——他们想成为这一环境承诺的一部分。”不清楚的是，这些是旧客户对升级感到满意，还是新客户从不愿牺牲的品牌迁移过来。<br>
Luthy told me that consumers are rewarding "human brands" that display honesty, transparency, and a willingness to admit when they are wrong. Brand sacrifice also reflects the idea that consumers are holding companies to stricter standards than they hold for themselves. He noted that many people think it's a good idea to take fewer flights in general, but data reveals that air travel is up-few individuals seem willing to cut their own flying. When it comes to corporate behaviour, however, Luthy says that “no hypocrisy is allowed, [and] the standards are getting higher". The Trendwatching report cites an Accenture/Havas Media study that showed that 72 percent of respondents felt that “business is failing to takecare of the planet and society as a whole”<br>
Luthy告诉我，消费者正在奖励那些展示诚实、透明并愿意承认错误的“人性化品牌”。品牌牺牲还反映了消费者对公司要求比对自己更严格的想法。他指出，许多人认为减少飞行总是一个好主意，但数据显示航空旅行量在增加——很少有人愿意减少自己的飞行量。然而，当涉及到公司行为时，Luthy表示，“不允许虚伪，标准越来越高”。Trendwatching的报告引用了Accenture/Havas Media的一项研究，显示72%的受访者认为“商业未能照顾好地球和整个社会”。<br>
Companies may actually be in the best position to make such sacrifices, their strategies often require long-term vision and commitments For example, the companies in the Roundtable on Sustainable Palm Oil(RSPO) understand that if they don't help create an ecologically viable supply of this vital ingredient, their value chains will be riskier and less resilient, CVS's strategic intent is to become a bigger player in health beyond selling over-the-counter and prescription drugs and removing tobacco products aligns with that direction. When Coca-Cola ran a Supel Bowl ad that featured “America the Beautiful” sung in eight languages by people of various ethnicities, the firm was making a values-based statement, according to Luthy. The sacrifice? “They alienated some core customers" in order to champion diversity, he said. One cannot doubt that the company is aware of demographic trends that make courting a wide range of ethnic groups essential to business success, despite the potential loss of some current consumers.<br>
公司可能实际上最有能力做出这种牺牲，他们的战略通常需要长期愿景和承诺。例如，圆桌可持续棕榈油（RSPO）的公司明白，如果他们不帮助创建这一重要成分的生态可行供应，他们的价值链将更加风险和脆弱。CVS的战略意图是成为健康领域的更大参与者，超越销售非处方药和处方药，去除烟草产品符合这一方向。可口可乐在超级碗广告中使用了由不同种族的人用八种语言演唱的《美丽的美国》，根据Luthy的说法，这是一种基于价值的声明。牺牲是什么？“他们疏远了一些核心客户”以倡导多样性，他说。毫无疑问，公司意识到人口趋势使得吸引广泛的族群对商业成功至关重要，尽管可能会失去一些现有消费者。<br>
Consumers, on the other hand, are fickle. A recent story in the New York Times reported that people were ditching their hybrids for SUV snow that gas prices have taken a dive; it seems that environmental consciousness falls prey to short-term economics. That's not surprising as a fair number of the original purchases of hybrids were likely driven by high fuel prices, not concern for carbon levels in the atmosphere. We humans prize immediate gratification.<br>
另一方面，消费者是善变的。《纽约时报》最近的一篇报道指出，由于油价下跌，人们正在放弃混合动力车转向SUV；看起来，环境意识屈服于短期经济学。这并不令人惊讶，因为相当多的混合动力车原始购买者可能是受高油价驱动的，而不是对大气中碳水平的关注。我们人类珍视即时满足。<br>
The lessons for executives in all of this: Forward-looking companies can take a leadership position that uses sacrifice to build enduring customer allegiance and perhaps even boost immediate sales. More importantly, it can help leaders clarify a company's purpose, values, and performance. With all of those benefits, brand sacrifice might not be such a sacrifice after all.<br>
所有这些对高管的教训是：有前瞻性的公司可以通过牺牲来建立持久的客户忠诚度，甚至可能提高即时销售额。更重要的是，它可以帮助领导者明确公司的目标、价值和绩效。拥有所有这些好处，品牌牺牲可能根本不算是牺牲。]]></description><link>U1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">U1.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 15:53:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>